Guide to the William Morehead papers, 1834-1898 and undated RL.10045
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Morehead papers
1834-1898 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Morehead, William
RL.10045
3 Linear Feet
William Morehead was a merchant from Cumberland, Maryland. This collection contains correspondence, account books, bills, receipts, and advertisements, dealing with Morehead's household goods store. Collection also contains letters from firms in Maryland, Virginia, New York, Pennsylvania, Ohio, and West Virginia, pertaining to the sale, purchase, and shipment of goods, borrowing of money, payment of notes, and other matters.
Biographical note
William Morehead was the operator of a household furnishing goods store in Cumberland, Maryland.
Collection Overview
This collection contains correspondence to William Morehead from various business establishments in Maryland, New York, Pennsylvania, Ohio, and West Virginia. The letters pertain to all phases of Morehead’s business transactions including sale and purchase of goods, particularly stoves and water pumps, shipment of goods, borrowing of money, payment of promissory notes, and other matters. The collection also contains numerous advertisements, bills and receipts, and eighteen account books recording the sales and expenses of Morehead's store during the 1860's and 1870's.
Provenance
The William Morehead papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1955.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Merchants -- Maryland -- Cumberland; House furnishings industry and trade -- Maryland; Cumberland (Md.) -- Commerce; Maryland -- Commerce; Morehead, William
- William Morehead Papers, 1834-1898 and undated; 1
  - Papers, 1834-1866 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1867 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1868 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1869 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1870 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1871-1876 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1885-1898 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, Circa 1820s-1850s (Box 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1860s; 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1870s; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1870s; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Bills and Receipts, undated (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1864 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1866 (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1868-1870 (Box 2)
  - Ledger, Circa 1869 (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1869-1872 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1870-1871 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1871-1872 (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1872-1873 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1872-1876 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1873 (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1873 (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1873-1874 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1874 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1874 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1875 (Box 2)
  - Cash Book, 1875-1876 (Box 2)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 2)
  - Account Book, 1865-1866 (Box 3)